Bryan Pitman

355 Berry St #228 San Francisco, CA 94158

(510) 502-4658 pitman.bryan@gmail.com

Highly adaptable Operations Manager, trusted for over a decade to scale out the business in regional areas with the most growth potential while navigating a highly regulated environment. Regional jurisdiction includes the Bay Area and most of Northern CA up to the Oregon border. In charge of over 50 locally and remote staffed employees including 30 direct partner repair facilities.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GEICO - Regional Manager, Northern California (2017-2021)

Previously: Auto Damage Supervisor, East Bay, CA (2011 -2017), Supervisor Prep Program (2010 - 2011), Auto Damage Adjuster, East Bay, CA (2008 - 2010)

2017-PRESENT

Leadership

- Trusted to lead #1 revenue locale (San Francisco), in Q3 2019 in addition to the rest of Northern CA territories
- o In <15 months, developed aggressive city-level plans to create a competitive advantage in 8 key markets
- Liaison with CA Department of Insurance and Better Business Bureau to communicate updated and modern business practices to benefit policyholders
- o Increased overall claim customer service satisfaction from 88% to 93% for drivable vehicles repaired within the network in 2016

Process

- o Improved re-inspection accuracy to the 99th percentile in 2018 & 2019 despite the highest frequency of claims in the state; lowest loss leakage audit results in the USA
- o Increased market competitive advantage (CCC data) in Alameda county from #5 in 2014 to #1 2017 in Alameda County; reduced average severity by \$188 per claim and drove digit growth in policies sold
- Drove competitive rates with repair partners to historic lows
 – maximized efficiency by reducing cycle time
 by 2.5 days and rental variance by .8 days

• Career and People Management

- o Hired over 25 adjustors since 2017 with an 85% retention rate, 35% above the state average
- Selected for management training as a top 20% adjustor performance. Directly mentored by the regional VP, I worked in multipole cross-functional groups such as customer service, business, sales, HR, underwriting, and finance departments over a 12-month rotation
- Created processes to develop rising talent for Ops roles with a total of 8 promotions secured for staff since 2018
- Developed insights for adjusters and supervisors for immediate impact on those without analytical skillset.

- Developed multiple product pilots which grew to statewide mandates:
 - Piloted a new direct repair facility program increasing partnerships by 50% and lowered overall severity by 8.6%
 - o First independent appraiser process with ACES for rare and high-value vehicles
 - Developed advanced techniques with non-MSO key repair facilities to repair polycarbonate material,
 saving >\$500k in the local region and >\$12M across CA as the pilot was expanded statewide.
 - Under pressure to meet growing demand while understaffed, I developed our first virtual adjustment program, increasing throughput of volume without additional staffing, which grew the local market sector by 28% in 18 months. Still in use today.
- Built a strong understanding of product needs, customer pain points, and company economics through
 negotiating settlement of property damage claims with policyholders, claimants, attorneys, small claims court
 mediators, and repair facilities

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley, CA

BA Environmental Economics & Policy

General Assembly

Advance Excel, Advanced Data Analysis, Advanced SQL Bootcamp

CERTIFICATIONS

ICAR Platinum

Since 2018

ACCOLADES

2018 California Manager of the Year

GEICO Biennial Auto Damage Conference